ip.com 2018-08-02

# Privacy Policy - IP.com

At IP.com, we respect your privacy. We want to ensure that you get the information, content, and experiences that matter most to you. IP.com is committed to protecting the privacy of its customers, partners, and other contacts.

This privacy policy does not apply to information that is publicly available as made in patent filings and other public repositories.

**Scope**

This privacy policy applies to all personal data processed by full-time and part-time employees, when acting on behalf of IP.com, contractors and partners doing business on behalf of IP.com, as well as all legal entities, all operating locations, and all business processes conducted by IP.com.

**What information do we collect?**

IP.com collects the following personal data in line with the use purposes explained in a subsequent section:

– Your name and contact details  
– Online profile data/usage  
– Purchasing and payment information  
– Registration and participation in IP.com events and activities  
– Product preferences  
– Information about the device(s) you use  
– Cookies  
– Authentication data  
– Location information  
– Other information you upload or provide to us

**How do we use your information?**

IP.com uses (and, where specified, shares) your personal information for the following purposes:

**To process transactions.  **IP.com uses personal information such as name, physical address, telephone number, email address, and company/institution to engage in interactions with you, including contacting you about your account, publishing, or event participation. We use financial/credit card and payment information to process your order and may need to share some of this information with delivery services, credit card clearing houses, and other third parties to complete the transaction.

**To provide support or other services.**  IP.com may use your personal information to provide you with support or other services that you have ordered or requested. IP.com may also use your personal information to respond directly to your requests for information, including registrations for newsletters, webinars, or other specific requests, or pass your contact information to the appropriate IP.com partners for further follow-up related to your interests.

**To provide information based on your needs and respond to your requests.  **IP.com may use your personal information to provide you with notices of new product releases and service developments.

**To administer products.  **IP.com may contact you if you purchase products to confirm certain information about your order (for example, that you did not experience problems in the download/log-in process). We may also use this information to confirm compliance with licensing and other terms of use and may share it with your company/institution.

**To select content, improve quality, and facilitate use of the websites.  **IP.com may use your personal information, including the information gathered as a result of site navigation and electronic protocols and cookies (including third-party cookies), to help create and personalize website content, improve website quality, track marketing campaign responsiveness, evaluate page response rates, conduct usability testing, and facilitate your use of the websites (for example, to facilitate navigation and the login process, avoid duplicate data entry, enhance security, keep track of shopping cart additions, and preserve order information between sessions).

**To assess usage of IP.com products and services.  **IP.com may track your usage of IP.com products and services to determine your level of usage, and those usage statistics may be made available to IP.com’s business partners.

**To communicate with you about a meeting, conference, or event.  **We may communicate with you about a meeting, conference, or event hosted or co-sponsored by IP.com or one of our business associates. This may include information about the event’s content, event logistics, updates, and additional information related to the event. Information you provide when registering for or participating in a conference managed or co-sponsored by parties, other than or in addition to IP.com may be shared with those parties, and the treatment of such information is further subject to the privacy policies of those parties. IP.com and its conference co-sponsors may contact you after the event about the event, subsequent iterations of the event and related events. Please note that IP.com conference, meeting or event organizers, co-sponsors, exhibitors, and other third parties may directly request your personal information at their conference booths or presentations. Providing your information to them is optional, and you should review their privacy policies to address your particular needs and concerns about how they will treat your personal information.

** ** **To protect IP.com content and services.  **We may use your information to prevent potentially illegal activities and to enforce our terms and conditions. We also use a variety of technological systems to detect and address anomalous activity and to screen content to prevent abuse, such as spam. These efforts may, on occasion, result in a temporary or permanent suspension or termination of some functions for some users

** ** **To get feedback or input from you.  **In order to deliver products and services of most interest to our customers, from time to time, we may ask members, customers, volunteers, and website visitors to provide us input and feedback (for example through surveys, usability studies, focus groups).

**To protect IP.com information assets as well as your own personal data.  **Our security program protects the confidentiality, integrity, and availability of IP.com information assets by following a risk management approach based on policies, standards, guidelines, and procedures to meet security objectives while supporting business and operational goals.

**Your Use of the IP.com Website**

Like many websites, IP.com uses commonly used information gathering tool, such as cookies and web beacons, to collect information as you navigate the IP.com website.  IP.com also automatically collects certain information, such as internet protocol (IP address), browser type, operating system and other usage information, and stores that information in log files.  We use this information to analyze trends, administer the IP.com website, track your navigation around our website, serve targeted advertising and gather broad demographic information.

**Cookies and web beacons**.

Cookies are small data files that a website places on your hard drive for record-keeping purposes.  Web beacons are transparent pixel images that are used in collecting information about website usage.  They assist us in making your interactions with IP.com easy and meaningful by providing enhanced functionality and aggregate traffic data. Standing alone, neither cookies nor web beacons personally identify you.  Unless you choose to identify yourself to IP.com (e.g., by filling out a web form) or have previously identified yourself to IP.com, you remain anonymous to us.

You have many choices with regards to the management of cookies on your computer.  All major browsers allow you to block or delete cookies from your system, but if you choose to block or delete cookies, it may limit your use of certain features or functions on IP.com.  To learn more about your ability to manage cookies and web beacons, please consult the privacy features in your browser.

**Third Party Advertisers.**

Please note that at times, third parties may set cookies or use related technologies or web beacons when you view and/or click their advertising banners, links or other ads. Information from tracking technologies received with third party ads and links may be collected directly by those advertisers and ad service providers and used to cause relevant ads to be displayed to you. For example, these companies may collect and use information about you and your visits to IP.com and other websites in order to provide advertisements about goods and services of interest to you. These advertisements may appear on IP.com and on other websites. The advertiser’s privacy policy and/or that of its service provider will govern the use of this information and we are not responsible for the privacy practices of such companies. We encourage you to read these businesses’ privacy policies to learn about how they treat your information. Additionally, some of these companies (like the ad networks) are members of the industry groups, the Network Advertising Initiative and the Digital Advertising Alliance, each of which offers a single location to opt out of their cookies. For more information about third party advertisers and how to prevent them from using your information, we encourage you to visit the Network Advertising Initiative’s consumer web site, at http://www.networkadvertising.org/choices, and the Digital Advertising Alliance’s consumer choice page at http://www.aboutads.info.

**Do Not Track.**

IP.com does not respond to web browser “do not track” signals or other similar mechanisms.

**Third Party Practices.**

IP.com may contain links to other websites that have their own separate terms and conditions and privacy policies.  We have no control over, and assume no responsibility for, the content, policies, and practices of any third-party websites.  The terms and conditions and privacy policies of such websites govern your use of the services offered on those websites.

**Security**

We employ reasonable and current security methods, including physical, technical and administrative safeguards, to prevent loss, misuse, unauthorized access, disclosure, alteration, and destruction of information.  We update and test our security technology on an ongoing basis.  When you voluntarily disclose personal information online, for example, in public areas or through email, others can collect and use such information.  No data transmission over the Internet or any wireless network can be guaranteed to be perfectly secure.  As a result, while we try to protect your personal information, we cannot ensure or guarantee the security of any information transmitted to us, and you transmit such information at your own risk.

**Transferring Personal Data from the EU to the US.**

IP.com has its headquarters in the United States.  Information we collect from you will be processed in the United States.  The United States has not sought nor received a finding of “adequacy” from the European Union.  IP.com collects and transfers to the United States only with your consent, to perform a contract with you, or to fulfill a compelling legitimate interest of IP.com in a manner that does not outweigh your rights and freedoms.  IP.com endeavors to apply suitable safeguards to protect the privacy and security of your personal data and to use it only consistent with your relationship with IP.com and the practices described in this privacy policy.  We also minimize the risk to your rights and freedoms by not collecting or storing sensitive information about you.

How can you control your information?

If you have concerns about your account information, we will work with you to review, revise and correct the personal data we have on file.  Contact us via phone at +1 585-427-8180, or, via email at [support@ip.com](mailto:support@ip.com), or use the unsubscribe method provided in our various communications or services.

**Children Under 13.**

You must be 13 years and older to register to use IP.com.  As a result, we do not specifically collect information about children.  If we learn that we have collected information from a child under the age of 13, we will delete the information as quickly as possible.

**For EU data subjects.**

The European Union’s General Data Protection Regulation and other countries’ privacy laws provide certain rights for data subjects.  Because IP.com is not established in the European Union, these rights only apply in relation to IP.com offering goods or services to data subjects in the European Union, or in relation to IP.com monitoring behavior in the European Union.  Among these rights is the right to know the purpose of the processing; the categories of personal data concerned; who else outside of IP.com might have received the data from us; what the source of the information was (if you did not provide it directly to us); and how long the data will be stored. Additionally, you have the right to access and rectify your personal data if it is inaccurate.  You may, under certain circumstances, also request that we cease using your data for direct marketing purposes, or that we erase your data.  You may also have a right to lodge a complaint with the appropriate data protection authority if you have concerns about how we process your personal data.  We will, at your request, provide personal data that you have provided to IP.com to you or transmit it directly to another controller if technically feasible.

**How will you know if the Privacy Policy is changed?**

IP.com may update its Privacy Policy from time to time. If we make any material changes we will notify you by email if you have an IP.com account, or by means of a notice on this website prior to the change becoming effective. We encourage you to periodically review this page for the latest information on our privacy practices.
